# Steve Mustanski

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/steve-mustanski

Profile: <u>stevemustanski.github.io</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/SteveMustanski</u>

## Software Developer/Teacher/Agilist

Diverse background including software development, teaching, and Agile delivery. Experience includes roles as a software engineer, teaching assistant, scrum master, and release train engineer. Passion for learning and helping others gain new skills. Able to effectively communicate with technical and non-technical stakeholders. Experience with both software and infrastructure delivery projects.

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS / TECHNOLOGIES**

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- jQuery
- Git/Github

- Cucumber
- React
- Angular
- AWS
- Java

- Scrum
- Kanban
- SAFe
- Lean Adaptive

Email: steve.mustanski@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# UNIVERSITY OF RICHMOND, Richmond, VA

**Teaching Assistant, Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp** 

2018 - Present

- Assist students in class and during office hours with homework assignments and projects.
- Grade and provide feedback on homework assignments and projects.

## CAPITAL ONE, Richmond, VA

1998 - Present

## Scrum Master, Card Data Transformation & AMP, February 2018 – Present

- Trained over 50 team members before and after google transition. Created instructional blog entries which
  received over 6,500 views during August and September helping employees make the transition from
  Outlook to G Suite.
- Achieved 40% and 70% epic cycle time reduction for two teams by teaching the teams how to focus on MVP and reducing work in progress.
- Presented bi-monthly brown bag sessions focusing on technical topics to increase scrum master understanding of tools and concepts used by their teams.

## Software Engineer, SEED program, April 2017 – January 2018

- Selected for and completed the two-month SEED developer boot camp.
- Created a single source of system behavior using gherkin enabling future test automation efforts and reduced conflicting requirements.
- Utilized Cucumber Java to create the team's first ever automated testing pattern testing both English and Spanish features without the need to duplicate test scenarios.
- Implemented the internally developed ReLISH reporting tool allowing improved management of the regression testing process, avoiding duplicate testing efforts, and reducing overall regression testing effort.
- Coordinated SEED brown bag sessions enabling knowledge sharing for current and past SEED program participants.

#### Scrum Master, Chariot and Content One, 2016 – 2017

- Participated in Lean Adaptive workshop and facilitated the teams adopting new, more effectively aligned processes, increasing team velocity and transparency.
- Migrated the team from Version One to Jira and conducted training sessions for team members transitioning to Jira reducing the team's learning curve.

 Coordinated AWS brown bag sessions for scrum masters enhancing scrum master understanding of cloud technologies.

## Scrum Master and Release Train Engineer, UPF and Chassis, 2013 – 2016

Coached and supported three UPF teams delivering an enterprise wide framework solution and the transition to a multi-team train for the delivery of the Chassis framework.

- Migrated the three UPF teams from Version One to Jira while expanding the teams into a 5-team train
  providing increased visibility of individual team activities and reducing the number of dependency related
  impediments.
- Introduced the concept of Agile planning and forecasting which increased the team's delivery predictability.
   This allowed for management to understand and act on the need for additional resources/teams and meet delivery deadlines.

## Scrum Master/Project Manager, WWW (Capitalone.com), 2010 – 2013

- Conceived and influenced the purchase of mobile devices for testing the responsive web design effort reducing the number of critical defects that would have been found post release.
- Advocated for and delivered multi-data center deployment strategy for the migration of LOBs to portal and subsequent releases with zero customer downtime.
- Delivered the infrastructure which supported the migration of WWW from PHP to web logic portal on-time allowing the software delivery teams to meet aggressive timelines.

## IT Manager/Project Manager, SSP, 2008 – 2010

- Managed the SSP platform from a small one team/ application platform to a multi-team/application platform.
- Managed the on-time delivery of the SSP platform and the first hosted application on the platform.
- Led the vendor selection process for the outsourcing of development activities resulting in the best capability/cost combination for the platform.

### **Scrum Master. WWW.** 2006 – 2008

- Trained delivery team in Agile scrum and facilitated the on-time delivery of three critical projects.
- Proposed cold site delivery strategy enabling the team to deliver the rebranding effort avoiding over 14 or more hours of estimated downtime for the Capital One customer facing web site.

# ETL developer/Tech Lead/Scrum Master, 1998 – 2006

Transitioned through roles from ETL developer to ETL Tech Lead to scrum master supporting several data warehousing, data migration, and data transformation efforts.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Richmond, Richmond, VA - 2009

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA - 2004

Bachelor of Science, Information Systems - Graduated Cum Laude

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate
- Certified Scrum Master
- SAFe Agilist
- PMP

# **AWARDS**

- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q3 2013 Responsive Web Design
- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q2 2008 Project 541
- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q2 2008 Card Lab Project
- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q2 2005 Project Charger
- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q3 2002 IBS to Recruiting project